Guide to the Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel Collection, 1876-2020 and undated, bulk 1950-2020 RL.10006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Visual Arts Materials, 1952-2012; undated; 1
  - Art, 1964-2004; undated; 1
    - Wurman, Richard Saul: New York is News, 1988, cloth and cut paper collage, 16x20 in. (Box 599)
    - Horton, "Portrait of a Young Woman," 1984, framed collage (Box 647)
  - Cultural Artifacts and Memorabilia, 1964-1989; undated; 2
    - African fetish doll decorated with beads, metal and cloth, undated, 4x17 in. (Box 580)
    - African fetish doll decorated with beads, metal and cloth, undated, 4.5x13 in. (Box 581)
    - African fetish doll decorated with beads, metal and cloth, undated, 4x9.5 in. (Box 582)
    - Bead and leather bracelet, undated, 3.0 in. (Box 584)
    - Beaded gourd, undated, 4x4 in. (Box 585)
    - Clay frog clave [percussion instrument], undated, 3.0x3.0 in. (Box 588)
    - Clay painted vase/jar, undated, 2.0x3.0 in. (Box 586)
    - Cut metal angel painted figure, undated, 3.0x5.0 in. (Box 590)
    - Engraved metal cross pendant on leather cord, undated, 2.0x2.5 in. (Box 590)
    - Fragment of Berlin Wall, November 1989, 2.0x2.0 in. (Box 588)
    - Happy anniversary booklet, undated, 2.0x2.0 in. (Box 589)
    - Metropolitan Opera souvenir curtain cord in wooden case with clear panel, 1966, 6.0x19.0 in. (Box 596)
    - One-sided Asian wood carving, undated, 4.5x8.0 in. (Box 587)
    - Painted gourd maraca, undated, 2.75x3.0 in. (Box 587)
    - Painted gourd maraca, undated, 3.5x4.5 in. (Box 586)
    - Painted wooden figure, undated, 1.5x3.5 in. (Box 586)
    - Painted wooden figure with feather, undated, 2.0x6.0 in. (Box 587)
    - Painted wooden figure with feather, undated, 2.0x7.0 in. (Box 587)
    - Painted wooden figure with feather, undated, 2.5x7.0 in. (Box 587)
    - Plastic Mississippi riverboat in a bottle, undated, 2.5x5.0 in. (Box 589)
    - Plastic Statue of Liberty snow cube, undated, 2.0x2.0 in. (Box 589)
    - Red cloth covered wooden plaque with wood door opening to a small painting, undated, 4.0x6.0 in. (Box 590)
    - Round box embellished with metal filigree, undated, 2.0x2.0 in. (Box 586)
    - Round wooden box, painted, with metal embellishments, undated, 5.0x5.0 in. (Box 588)
    - Straw broom, undated, 3.0x13.0 in. (Box 584)
    - Straw broom, undated, 2.0x7.0 in. (Box 584)
    - Tarot cards, two metal, one wax, one glass, undated, 2.5x4.5 in. (Box 585)
    - Thirty assorted political, organizational and event pins, undated (Box 589)
    - Wooden darning tool, undated, 1.0x8.0 in. (Box 584)
    - Wooden house figurine with wood-burn engravings, three holes on top, undated, 1.75x4.5 in. (Box 584)
  - Photographs, 1980-1998; undated; 3
    Contains black-and-white and color photographs that do not belong in another series or that were maintained as displayed art by Diamonstein-Spielvogel. Photographs vary in size. Descriptions and most titles were provided by the processing archivists. Arranged chronologically.
    - New York subway, by Susan Rutman, black-and-white, 1980 (Box 599)
    - Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel, black-and-white photograph, circa 1990 (Box 599)
    - Honolulu, Hawaii, by Evelyn H. Lauder, color photograph, 1992 (Box 600)
    - Neptune Fountain, by Bob Kodadeck, black-and-white, 1993 (Box 599)
    - Inle Lake, Myanmar, by Evelyn H. Lauder, color photograph, 1998 (Box 600)
    - Barbaralee Diamonstein-Spielvogel and Carl Spielvogel, color photograph on canvas, undated (Box 599)
    - Knotted tree trunk, by Norman Cousins, black-and-white photograph mounted on cardboard, undated (Box 600)
    - Shoreline, author unknown, color photograph mounted on cardboard, undated (Box 600)
    - The White House in spring, author unknown, color, undated (Box 598)
  - Prints, 1975-1996; undated; 4
    Subseries contains poster reproductions of art and print materials. Dimensions vary from 11x14 inches to 28x39 inches. Arranged alphabetically by title or brief description provided by the archivist.
    - American flag, signed by James Crawford, 1976 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Artists' Sets and Costumes, signed by Cletus Johnson, 1977 (Box 599)
    - The Big Apple, handwritten dedication to Carl Spielvogel, 1976 (Box 597)
    - Exploring the Media, signed by Dan Ben C'naan, Lynn McVeigh and Ruth Goldstein, 1975 (Box 599)
    - Gouache: "Grand Bal des Artistes" by Natalia Goncharova, with note signed by Albert, 1979 (Box 600)
    - Metropolitan Opera poster, signed by Igor Stravinsky, 1981-1982 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Louise Nevelson Stockholm exhibition poster, 1973 (Oversize-folder 4)
    - New York City, signed by artist Barry Ross, undated (Box 597)
    - Preserving the Past to Ensure the Future, 1996 (Box 599)
    - Southstreet Seaport by Ten Eyck, undated (Box 599)
    - Verejnost proti nasilu [The public against (force?)], signed, 1989 (Oversize-folder 2)
    - Woman power, 1970s (Oversize-folder 2)